📸 Hi there! To improve your experience, we use cookies, scripts, and similar tools on our site. These tools help us collect and share information with our partners to better understand how you use our services and provide you more relevant content, including targeted ads. By using our site, you agree to our [Terms of Use](https://vsco.co/about/terms-of-use) and [Privacy Policy](https://vsco.co/about/privacy-policy).

VSCO: Photo & Video Editor

Experiment with 200+ high-quality presets

Privacy Policy

Effective as of July 10, 2024.  
  
Please click [**here**](https://vsco.co/about/privacy-policy-old) to view the previous version of our Privacy Policy.

At VSCO, it’s important to us to be open and transparent with the creators who trust us with their data. This Privacy Policy describes our privacy practices and how we handle your data that we collect through our websites, products, services, social media, marketing activities, and other ways described in this Privacy Policy (collectively, our **“Services”**). This Privacy Policy supplements our [Terms of Use](https://vsco.co/about/terms-of-use). All provisions of our Terms of Use likewise apply to this Privacy Policy.

If you’re a resident of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Texas, Utah, or Virginia, check out the [U.S. State Law Privacy Rights section below](#) for some additional information about your personal information and rights under state law.

Table of Contents
-----------------

1. [Data we collect](#1-data-we-collect)
2. [How we use your data](#2-how-we-use-your-data)
3. [How we share your data](#3-how-we-share-your-data)
4. [How long we keep your data](#4-how-long-we-keep-your-data)
5. [Your choices](#5-your-choices)
6. [How we secure your data](#6-how-we-secure-your-data)
7. [International data transfer](#7-international-data-transfer)
8. [General audience service](#8-general-audience-service)
9. [Changes to this Privacy Policy](#9-changes-to-this-privacy-policy)
10. [How to contact us](#10-how-to-contact-us)
11. [U.S. State Law Privacy Rights](#11-state-law-privacy-rights)
12. [Privacy Notice to European Creators](#12-privacy-notice-to-european-countires)
13. [Privacy Notice for China Residents](#13-privacy-notice-for-china-residents)

#### Data we collect

There are three types of data we collect about you: data that you provide us, data we get through third parties, and data we collect automatically.

Here are some tables that summarize the different types of data we collect:

Data You Provide Us

Examples

**Account Data  
**We need certain information to set up your account.

Name, email address, phone number, username, password, redemption code, age, date of birth

**Profile Data  
**You can customize your profile on our Services so other creators can get to know you better.

Any information you add about yourself to your profile, such as your biographical details, photograph, social media links, interests, preferences

**Our Communications With You  
**Sometimes we might reach out to you, or you might reach out to us.

The communications between us when you contact us with questions, comments, or support requests

**Feedback  
**We would love to hear your thoughts on our Services.

Any feedback that you provide in any questionnaires, surveys, interviews, beta tests, or other scenarios in which we request your feedback

**Payment and Transactional Data  
**We need certain information about you so we can process your payments.

Name, country, payment card information, bank account number, billing information, subscription information, purchase history

**Marketing Data  
**We want to honor your choices regarding marketing efforts, and to understand how marketing campaigns are performing.

Your preferences for receiving marketing communications and details about your engagement with marketing communications

**User-Generated Content  
**You’ll get to interact with other creators and generate your own content when you use our Services.

Profile information, images, music, videos, collages, montages, comments, tags, collaborative areas that you create, your “favorite” content, the content you repost, messages, your interactions with VSCO’s content or other people’s content on our Services, and information you may provide to facilitate business between yourself and others.

**Data About Others  
**You might want to invite your friends to use our Services.

Contacts that you share with us

Date We Collect From Third Parties

Examples

**Data from Social Media Platforms  
**Sometimes you might connect with us on social media.

Your interactions with our social media posts, your mentions of VSCO or VSCO related hashtags in your social media posts

**Data from Other Creators  
**Our creators might want to invite you to use our Services.

Contact lists that other creators sync with our Services

**Data from your Single Sign On (SSO) Provider  
**We try to make the login process simpler for you by providing you with some SSO options.

**Data from your Single Sign On (SSO) Provider  
**We try to make the login process simpler for you by providing you with some SSO options.

**Data from Advertising Partners and Intermediaries  
**

We may receive information about you from third-party advertising partners and intermediaries, such as event data (e.g actions taken on a third party property, like purchases or downloads), email addresses, phone numbers, or other identifiers (e.g., cookie IDs, mobile advertising IDs, alternative IDs like LiveRamp RampIDs), or demographic or other analytical data.

**Data from Other Partners**

You might access VSCO through a partnership we have with another party. If so, that partner may share analytics information with us, error reporting, or other information needed for us to improve our Services or facilitate the partnership.

Data We May Collect Automatically

Examples

**Device Data  
**We receive certain information about your device and browser when you use our Services.

Operating system type and version, device type, device model, browser type, IP address, network information, unique identifiers, general location information

**Online Activity Data  
**We learn about how you’re engaging with us and our Services online.

Your interactions with different parts of our Services, including information you provide, the pages or profiles you are on, the content or ads you view or interact with, mouse movements, scrolling, keystroke and click activity, browsing and search behavior, the website that referred you to us, your interactions with us through our push notifications or other communications channels, whether you opened our marketing emails or clicked links within them.

**Metadata about Your Content  
**We get data about the content you contribute to our Services.

How, when, and where you created your content, how you edited your content, and other information you provide to us through comments, chat features, or other communications

We may automatically collect the data outlined above when you use our Services, read our emails, or otherwise interact with our Services through a computer or mobile device. We typically collect this information through a variety of first- or third-party tracking technologies, including cookies, web beacons, embedded scripts, APIs, mobile SDKs, location-identifying tools, and similar technologies, and we may otherwise use third-party partners to collect, monitor, or record this information. This information may be combined, either via such technologies or through another process, with information that you provided to us directly or information that we receive from a third party. You may be able to configure your browser and device settings to limit or disable the use of cookies or similar technologies. You can learn more in the “Your choices” section of this Privacy Policy.

#### How we use your data

Once we collect your data, we use it in a few different ways. This table summarizes the different ways we may use your data.

How We Use Your Data

What this means

**Delivering our Services  
**We’ll use your data to provide our Services to you.

We use your data to provide and enhance our Services and our business, establish, and maintain your account and profile, and related content, promote and facilitate business between yourself and businesses, enable security features, communicate with you about our Services, understand your needs and interests as they relate to our Services, personalize your experience with our Services, respond to your requests, questions, and comments, and invite your contacts that you invite to join our Services.

**Improving our Services  
**We may use your data to help us improve our products and services.

We use your data to monitor our Services, and to improve the performance and effectiveness of our Services, offers, advertising, communications features (such as live and automated chat), and customer service functionality. We may also use analytics tools to help us measure traffic and usage trends for our Services and to understand more about the demographics and behaviors of our creators.

**Research and Development  
**We might use your data to help us make our Services better.

We may use your data for research and development so we can understand and improve our Services.  
  
As part of these activities, we may also create aggregated, de-identified, or other anonymous data from personal information we collect. We make personal information into anonymous data by removing information that makes the data personally identifiable to you.

**Marketing  
**Depending on your choices, you might get marketing communications about our Services or other services.

**Direct marketing**. We may send you direct marketing communications about our Services or products or services that we offer with our marketing partners.  
  
If you would rather not receive our marketing emails, you can follow the steps in the “[Opt-Out of Marketing](https://vsco.co/about/privacy-policy#l5)” section later in this Privacy Policy.  
‍  
**Interest-based advertising**. We may engage third-party advertising partners to display ads on our Services and on third-party properties. These companies may use cookies and similar technologies in connection with our Services, our communications, and on other services, and use the information collected via such technologies to serve ads on our Services that they think will interest you (e.g., ads from third-party advertisers) or on other third-party properties (e.g., ads from VSCO or other ads that may interest you). This activity is typically called interest-based advertising or targeted advertising.  
  
We may also receive information about our creators from third-party advertising partners, which we then use to match to, and better understand, those creators or similar creators within our Services to serve targeted advertising to those creators on an advertiser’s behalf. Similarly, we may upload information about our creators to advertising partners to facilitate interest-based advertising to those users, or similar users, on our or other services. You can learn more about your choices for limiting interest-based advertising in the “Your choices” section of this Privacy Policy.  
  
We may also disclose information, such as event data, ad view/click data, and user identifiers, to advertising partners for purposes of measuring the effectiveness of ads (e.g., whether actions that you take on or off our Services were a result of ads that you may have seen or clicked on).  
‍  
Note that information we may receive from other sources may also be used for interest-based advertising purposes, such as information we receive that helps us better understand our users.

**Compliance and Protection  
**We may need to use your data in certain ways to make sure we provide our Services legally and safely.

To provide our Services, we must be mindful of the many legal, ethical, and contractual requirements that apply to us, while also trying to protect our creators and our Services.  
  
To that end, we might use your data as needed to comply with the law, respond to lawful data requests (like subpoenas and warrants), protect our creators, protect our rights (including by establishing and defending against legal claims), comply with any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements, enforce our terms and policies, and prevent or investigate fraudulent, harmful, or illegal activity.

#### How we share your data

We might need to share your data with other parties to help us do the things mentioned above. This table summarizes the other parties that might receive your data.

Who we might share your data with

Why we might share your data with them

Affiliates

We might share your data with our corporate affiliates or subsidiaries to do the things mentioned in this Privacy Policy.

Service Providers and Partners

We lean on certain companies and individuals that provide services on our behalf or help us operate our Services or our business. These service providers perform services like data hosting, email delivery and marketing activities, and provide or support features like chat and communications tools, information technology, customer service and website monitoring and analytics. We may also collaborate with other companies on partnerships intended to help distribute, enhance, or extend our Services or to bring you co-branded product experiences.

Advertising Partners and Intermediaries

We work with third-party advertising partners and intermediaries (e.g., ad networks, retargeters, sell-side or demand-side platforms, ad servers, clean rooms, identity resolution providers, measurement providers, publishers such as social media platforms or digital/print content providers, advertisers, agencies) to facilitate the delivery of advertising to you on VSCO or on third-party properties or to measure the effectiveness of those ads.  
  
You can learn about the options you have to opt-out of interest-based advertising in the “[Your Choices](#)” section of this Privacy Policy.

Professional Advisors

We may need to share your data with our professional advisors, like our lawyers, auditors, bankers, and insurers if it’s necessary for them to provide their services.

Authorities and Others

We may need to share your data with law enforcement, government authorities, and private parties if we need to do so for the compliance or protection purposes described above.

Business Transferees

If we go through a business transaction like a merger, acquisition, corporate divestiture, or dissolution (including bankruptcy), or a sale of all or some of our assets, we may share or transfer your data to the parties (or their advisors) to the transaction during the transaction or in contemplation of the transaction (including during due diligence).

Other Creators, Companies and the Public

Your profile and content are publicly visible and can be seen and used by others.  
  
We may create other ways you can interact and communicate with other creators, including things like tipping and other ways you can support creators monetarily. The data related to these interactions will be visible by other creators.  
  
We may also offer ways for you to interact with businesses that may wish to work with you, and your contact details may be made available to facilitate such potential interactions. More broadly, certain data relating to these interactions may be visible b businesses, other creators, and the public. 

We make commercially reasonable efforts to verify that any third parties who we share personal information with provide a level of protection of personal information that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. Except for service providers and affiliates, any such third parties may use such personal information as described in their own privacy policies or otherwise pursuant to their own practices. 

#### How Long We Keep Your Data

We retain data for as long as we need for the uses mentioned above. You can delete your account by following the instructions [**here**](https://support.vsco.co/hc/en-us/articles/360004196352-How-do-I-delete-my-VSCO-Account-).

When we don’t need your personal information anymore, we’ll either delete it or anonymize it, unless deletion or anonymization isn’t possible or practical (for example, because your data is in backup archives), in which case we’ll make sure your data is securely stored and isolated from further processing.

Remember that it is impossible to ensure that anything on the internet is ever completely removed. Even after your account is deleted, your content may still be visible, for example, if you’ve shared it on other platforms or if other people copied or shared your content before you deleted your account.

#### Your choices

You have control over your data in several ways. This table summarizes your choices concerning your data. If you’re located in California, Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Texas, Utah or Virginia, you can find additional information in the [U.S. State Law Privacy Rights](#) section below.

What you can do with your data

How to make it happen

Access or update your information

You can review and update certain account information by logging into your account.

Opt-out of marketing communications

You can opt-out of marketing-related emails by following the opt-out or unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of a marketing email, or by [**contacting us**](https://support.vsco.co/). You will continue to receive other non-marketing emails related to our Services. If you receive marketing text messages from us, you can opt out by replying STOP to our marketing message.

Adjust cookie preferences

You can opt out of the use of certain cookies and similar technologies by clicking “Your Privacy Choices” in the footer of the website and adjusting your preferences. Additionally, most browsers let you limit or reject cookies by configuring your browser settings accordingly.

Disable mobile location data

You can disable our access to your device’s geolocation in your mobile device settings.

Decline to provide information

You can decide not to give us certain data, but then you may not be able to use certain features of our Services.

Configure third party platform settings

If you connect to our Services through a third party platform (like a social media account), you may be able to use your settings in your account with that platform to limit the information we receive from it moving forward.

Delete your data

You can choose to delete certain content of yours from your account. You can delete your account and your data entirely by following the instructions [**here**](https://support.vsco.co/hc/en-us/articles/360004196352-How-do-I-delete-my-VSCO-Account-).  
  
If you are under 18 years of age, you can also use these same instructions to exercise your right to delete your content under California’s “Online Eraser” Law.

Opt-out of interest-based advertising

You can opt out of receiving interest-based advertising on websites through participating members of the Network Advertising Initiative by clicking [**here**](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1) or the Digital Advertising Alliance by clicking [**here**](https://optout.aboutads.info/). You can also opt out of receiving interest-based advertising in mobile apps through participating members of the Digital Advertising Alliance by using the AppChoices mobile app. Please note that we may work with companies that may not participate in these opt-out mechanisms but may offer their own opt-out.

Limit advertising ID use in your mobile settings

You may be able to configure your mobile device to limit how your mobile advertising ID can be used for interest-based advertising purposes.

#### How we secure your data

We use technical, organizational, and physical safeguards to protect your data, like firewalls and other security technology. For example, when you enter confidential information (such as login credentials or information submitted from within our Services), we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). However, there is always risk when doing anything on the internet, so we can’t guarantee 100% security of your data. If we find out that we’ve had a data breach and your personal information has been compromised, we’ll notify you as required by law and take appropriate steps to investigate and remedy the vulnerability.

#### International data transfer

We’re headquartered in the United States and may use service providers in other countries. Your data may be processed or stored in the United States or other countries outside of where you live, which may have data protection laws that are different from those in your country. When we transfer data across borders, we take measures to comply with the relevant data protection laws governing the transfer.

#### General audience service

Our Services are intended for a general audience. As such, they are not directed or targeted toward children under 13 years of age and are not intended for use by children under 13. If we learn that we collected data through our Services from a child under 13 without the consent of the child’s parent or guardian as required by law, we will delete it.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy. If we make any material change to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you via email, through a notification posted on our Services, or as otherwise permitted or required by law. In all cases, your use of our Services after the effective date mentioned in any updated Privacy Policy indicates your acceptance of the updated Privacy Policy.

#### How to contact us

* **Online:** [**https://support.vsco.co**](https://support.vsco.co/)
* **Mail:** VSCO, Attention: Legal Department, 548 Market St, Suite 92958, San Francisco, CA 94104

‍

U.S. State Privacy Rights
-------------------------

This section provides additional disclosures to California, Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Texas, Utah, and Virginia residents under their respective state privacy laws, including further information on their rights under such laws.

In this section, when we use the term “personal information” we mean it (or similar term, such as “personal data”) as it is defined under those laws. 

**Verification.** We’ll need enough detail to understand and respond to your request. We may need to verify your identity to process your requests and may also need to confirm your state residency. To verify your identity, we may require a combination of government identification, a copy of the receipt for your VSCO membership, or other information. We may also require you to login from a verified valid device or verify that the device you’re logging in from is valid.

**Authorized Agents.** You can have an authorized agent make a request on your behalf, but we’ll need to verify your agent’s identity. We would also need a copy of a valid power of attorney, or a written and signed permission to exercise your privacy rights on your behalf. We may still need to verify your identity and may ask you to directly confirm that you provided your authorized agent permission to submit the request on your behalf.

**Sensitive Information.** We process “sensitive personal information” (or similar term, such as “sensitive data”) only as reasonably expected for providing theservices that you’ve requested or as otherwise permitted without requiring a corresponding right to restrict or limit such use.

**Profiling.** We do not undertake any “profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects” on our creators.

**Retention.** The duration of how long we retain personal information is generally based on how long we need it for the purposes for which it was collected, which includes complying with our legal obligations.

#### Your Privacy Rights

You have certain rights regarding your personal information under the state consumer privacy laws listed above, subject to certain exceptions under such applicable law. Here, we provide a summary of your rights relating to personal information and how to exercise them. You are entitled to exercise these rights free from discrimination.

**Access.** You have the right to access a copy of your personal information, which you can do by following the instructions available [**here**](https://support.vsco.co/hc/en-us/articles/360052896671-How-do-I-access-a-copy-of-my-personal-data-on-VSCO-), or by submitting a request [**here**](https://vsco.formstack.com/forms/vsco_data_request).

**Correction.** You have the right to request that we correct inaccurate personal information that we have collected about you. You can do so by submitting a support request [**here**](https://support.vsco.co/hc/en-us), or by submitting a request [**here**](https://vsco.formstack.com/forms/vsco_data_request).

**Deletion.** You have the right to request deletion of the personal information that we have collected from you, which you can do by following the instructions available [**here**](https://support.vsco.co/hc/en-us/articles/360004196352-How-do-I-delete-my-VSCO-Account-), or by submitting a request [**here**](https://vsco.formstack.com/forms/vsco_data_request). But if we delete your personal information, we might not be able to provide our Services to you.

**Opting out of “sales,” “sharing,” and processing for “targeted advertising” purposes.**

Like many companies, we work with advertising partners and intermediaries (e.g., ad networks, retargeters, sell-side or demand-side platforms, ad servers, clean rooms, identity resolution providers, measurement providers, publishers such as social media platforms or digital/print content providers, advertisers, agencies) to help deliver targeted ads to you on VSCO or other properties based on your activity across unrelated properties (e.g., your activity on VSCO and social media networks or other digital properties) and to measure the effectiveness of such ads.  

Through the use of cookies or other tracking technologies, we make personal information (e.g., device data tied to online activity data, identity data such as email addresses or phone numbers) available to such partners or intermediaries for such purposes. We may also upload information (e.g., email address, phone number) about our creators to these partners or intermediaries to facilitate such purposes. In either case, under certain state consumer privacy laws, these disclosures of personal information may be considered a “sale” or “share” (or processing for “targeted advertising” more generally) unless certain exceptions apply (e.g., disclosing personal information to a “service provider” or “processor,” where applicable).

If we know that you’re 13-15 years of age, we won’t “sell”or “share” your Personal Information unless we get your consent to do so.

‍_Opting out of “Sales,” “Shares,” and“Targeted Advertising” Involving Cookies or Other Tracking Technologies_

You can opt-out of "sales,” “shares,” and processing for “targeted advertising” that occur via cookies or other tracking technologies by clicking **Your Privacy Choices** in our website footer below and opting out of “Targeting Cookies”. Your request to opt-out will apply only to the browser on the device from which you submit the request, and, if you delete your cookies, you will need to opt-out again in a subsequent session on this website. Alternatively, for this opt-out in relation to cookies and other tracking technologies, you can also broadcast the Global Privacy Control (GPC) to opt-out on each participating browser on the device that you’re using. Learn more at the [**Global Privacy Control website**](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/).

To opt-out of “sales/shares” or processing for “targeted advertising” that do not rely on third-party advertising partners or intermediaries’ tracking technologies on this website (e.g., upload of users’ email addresses to other social media platforms to target them with ads), you must also opt out by submitting a request [here](https://vsco.formstack.com/forms/vsco_data_request) (also accessible via our **Your Privacy Choices** link).

**Appeals.** If you are a Colorado, Connecticut, Motana, Oregon, Texas, or Virginia resident, you may appeal our refusal to take action on a request exercising one of your rights mentioned above by contacting our [Support Team.](https://support.vsco.co/hc/en-us)

**Right to Know.** If you’re a California resident, you have the right to know the following as it relates to the last 12 months: the categories of PersonalInformation that we’ve collected about you, the categories of sources from which we’ve collected the Personal Information, the business or commercial purpose for collecting, selling,” or “sharing” the Personal Information, the categories of recipients to whom we’ve disclosed the personal information for a business purpose, and the categories of third parties to whom the personal information was “sold” or “shared.” You can find this information in the table below.

CCPA category of Personal Information (PI)

Examples of PI we collect in this category

Source of PI

Business and commercial purposes for collection

Categories of recipients to whom we “disclose” PI for a business purpose

**Categories of third parties to whom we sell or share PI for interest-based advertising**

Identifiers

Account data, profile data, data about others, our communications with you, identifiers, data about others

You or Third party sources

Delivering our Services, Research and development, Marketing, and Compliance and protection

Affiliates, Service Providers, Professional advisors, Authorities and others, Business transferees, and other creators and the public

Advertising Partners and Intermediaries

California Customer Records (as defined in California Civil Code section 1798.80)

Account data, profile data, our communications with you, feedback, payment and transactional data, your content, data about others

You

Delivering our Services, Research and development, Marketing, and Compliance and protection

Service Providers, Professional advisors, Authorities and others, Business transferees, and other creators and the public

Advertising Partners and Intermediaries

Commercial Information

Payment and transactional data, marketing data, feedback, online activity data

You or Automatic collection

Delivering our Services, Research and development, Marketing, and Compliance and protection

Service Providers, Professional advisors, Authorities and others, and Business transferees

Advertising Partners and Intermediaries

Online Identifiers

Profile data, device data

You or Automatic collection

Delivering our Services, Research and development, Marketing, and Compliance and protection

Service Providers, Professional advisors, Authorities and others, Business transferees, and other creators and the public

Advertising Partners and Intermediaries

Internet or Network Information

Marketing data, device data, and online activity data

You or Automatic collection

Delivering our Services, Research and Development, Marketing, and Compliance and protection

Service Providers, Professional advisors, Authorities and others, and Business transferees

Advertising Partners and Intermediaries

Geolocation Data

Device data and metadata about certain content of creators

Automatic collection

Delivering our Services, Research and development, Marketing, and Compliance and protection

Business partners, Service Providers, Professional advisors, Authorities and others, Business transferees, and other creators & the public

Advertising Partners and Intermediaries

Inferences

May be derived from your: Payment & transactional data, marketing data, content of creators, device data, online activity data

N/A

Delivering our Services, Research and development, Marketing, and Compliance and protection

Business partners, Service Providers, Authorities and others, and Business transferees

Advertising Partners and Intermediaries

Protected Classification Characteristics

We do not intentionally collect this information, but it may be revealed in identity data, content of creators, or other information we collect

N/A

N/A

N/A

N/A

Sensory Information

Creator content (images, video or audio)

You

Delivering our Services, Research and development, Marketing, and Compliance and protection

Authorities and others, Service Providers, and Business transferees

N/A

Sensitive Personal Information

We do not intentionally collect this information, but it may be revealed in content of creators

N/A

N/A

N/A

N/A

\* Note: You might voluntarily provide additional information to us, which may contain other categories of personal information not mentioned in this table.

Privacy Notice to European Creators
-----------------------------------

The information provided in this notice applies only to individuals in the European Economic Area, United Kingdom and Switzerland (collectively, “**Europe**”) and explains our practices regarding personal data that we collect from you or which we have obtained about you from a third party, and the legal bases for processing your personal data. It also describes your rights in respect to our processing of your personal data.

**Personal data.** “Personal data” as used in this notice has the same meaning given in European data protection legislation.

**Controller.** VSCO is the controller of your personal data covered by this Privacy Policy for purposes of European data protection legislation.

**Data protection representative**. Our data protection representative in the EU and UK is VeraSafe. You may contact them at:

* **VeraSafe Ireland Ltd.**, Unit 3D North Point House, North Point Business Park, New Mallow Road, Cork T23AT2P, Ireland
* **VeraSafe United Kingdom Ltd.**, 37 Albert Embankment, London SE1 7TL, United Kingdom

**Legal bases for processing****. We use your personal data only as permitted by law. Our legal bases for processing personal data are described in the table below.**

**Processing purpose  
  
**‍_Details regarding each processing purpose listed below are provided in the section of our Privacy Policy titled “How we use your data”._

Legal basis

Processing is necessary to perform the contract governing our provision of our Services or to take steps that you request prior to signing up for our Services. If we have not entered into a contract with you, we process your personal data based on our legitimate interest in providing our Services you access and request.

[**Research and development  
‍  
‍**](#)[**Marketing  
‍  
‍**](#)[**Compliance and protection  
‍  
‍**](#)**As otherwise described in the Privacy Policy**

These activities constitute our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for these activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).

Processing activities for which you have consented

Processing is based on your consent. Where we rely on your consent, you have the right to withdraw it any time in the manner indicated when you consent or in our Services.

**Use for new purposes**. We may use your personal data for reasons not described in this Privacy Policy where permitted by law and the reason is compatible with the purpose for which we collected it. If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and explain the applicable legal basis.

**Retention**. We retain personal data for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we collected it, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements, to establish or defend legal claims, or for fraud prevention purposes.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

When we no longer require the personal data we have collected about you, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal data has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal data and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. If we anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you), we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**Sensitive personal data**. We ask that you not provide us with any sensitive personal data (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through our Services, or otherwise to us.

If you provide us with any sensitive personal data to us when you use our Services, you are consenting to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data, you must not submit such sensitive personal data through our Services.

**Your rights****. You have the following rights in relation to the personal data we hold about you:**

* **Right of access**: You can ask us if we are processing your personal data and to provide you with a copy of it (along with certain details). If you require additional copies, we may need to charge a reasonable fee.
* **Right to rectification**: If the personal data we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to request to have it rectified.
* **Right to erasure**: You can ask us to delete or remove your personal data in some circumstances such as where we no longer need it or if you withdraw your consent to our processing of your personal data (where applicable).
* **Right to restrict processing**: You can ask us to 'block' or suppress the processing of your personal data in certain circumstances, such as where you contest the accuracy of that personal data.
* **Right to data portability**: You have the right, in certain circumstances, to obtain personal data you have provided us with (in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format) and to reuse it elsewhere or to ask us to transfer this to a third party of your choice.
* **Right to object**: You can ask us to stop processing your personal data, and we will do so, if we are:
* **relying on our own or someone else's legitimate interests to process your personal data, unless we can demonstrate compelling legal grounds for the processing; or**
* **processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes.**
* **Right to withdraw consent**: If we rely on your consent (or explicit consent) as our legal basis for processing your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.
* **Right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority**: If you have a concern about any aspect of our privacy practices, including the way we have handled your personal data, you can report it to the relevant supervisory authority. You can find your data protection regulator [**here**](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en).

You may submit these requests through our [**Help Center**](http://support.vsco.co/). We may request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and process your request. Applicable law may require or permit us to decline your request. If we decline your request, we will tell you why, subject to legal restrictions.

**Cross-border data transfer**. If we transfer your personal data out of Europe to a country not deemed to provide an adequate level of personal data protection for purposes of applicable data protection laws such that additional safeguards are required, the transfer will be performed:

* pursuant to the recipient’s compliance with Standard Contractual Clauses or Binding Corporate Rules;
* pursuant to the consent of the individual to whom the personal data pertains; or
* as otherwise permitted by applicable laws.

You may contact us through our [**Help Center**](http://support.vsco.co/) if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of Europe.

**Privacy Notice for China Residents**
--------------------------------------

If you are a resident based in the mainland of China, we will collect, store, use, process, transfer, provide, disclose and delete (collectively referred to as the “**Process**”, “**Processing**” or “**Processed**”) your personal data in accordance with the PRC Personal Information Protection Law (“**PIPL**”) and the relevant applicable laws. The terms used in this Privacy Notice for China Residents have the definitions given to them under PIPL, including terms such as “**data processor**” and “**data controller**.”

#### Legal basis

Unlike in other jurisdictions, a legitimate interest is not a justified legal basis to process personal data in China. Consequently, we will obtain your proper consent for processing of your personal data as required by the PIPL and other relevant laws.

**You hereby grant your separate consent to the cross-border data collection and other relevant data processing activities set forth in this Privacy Policy. In the event of any material change of the purpose or method of processing or the type of personal data we process, we will re-obtain your consent.**

We will secure your separate consent if we undertake any of the following data processing activities in a manner that materially differs from this Privacy Policy:

* Processing of sensitive personal data;
* Use of personal data in automated decision-making;
* Provision of personal data to another personal data processor
* Disclosure of the personal data we Processed to the public; or
* Cross-border collection of your personal data

For the avoidance of any doubt, “sensitive personal data” refers to the personal data that is likely to result in damage to the personal dignity of any natural person or damage to his or her personal or property safety once disclosed or illegally used, including such information as biometric identification, religious belief, specific identity, medical health, financial account and precise geolocation, as well as the personal data of minors under the age of 14.

The processing of sensitive personal data is only for a specific purpose and sufficient necessity, and strict protection measures must be taken to ensure its data security.

**Data we collect from you**

Please see the above section “Data we collect” for details on the categories of data we collect from you.

**Purpose and method to Process your data**

Please see the above section “How we use your data” for details on how we process your personal data. Unless otherwise stated in the Privacy Notice for China Residents, the relevant sections in the Privacy Policy will apply regarding our processing of your personal data.

**How long and where your data will be retained**

We will collect your personal data from the United States and process your personal data in the United States. We will take necessary measures to ensure that the direct collection and other processing activities of your personal data comply with the relevant regimes under the PIPL.

Please see the above section "How Long We Keep Your Data” on the retention period of your personal data.

#### Your Rights

As a data subject, you have the following rights:

**Right to know and make decisions**. You have the right to be informed and to decide on the Processing of your personal data, as well as the right to restrict or deny another person from the Processing of your personal data, unless otherwise provided by the relevant laws and regulations of PRC.

**Right to access and make copies**. You have the right to access or make copies of your personal data from us, unless otherwise provided by the relevant laws and regulations of PRC.

**Right of portability**. We will provide a way for transfer where you request to transfer your personal data to another personal data processor you designate, provided that the conditions prescribed by the PRC national cybersecurity authority are met.

**Right to correct and complete.** If you discover that your personal data is incorrect or incomplete, you have the right to request us to correct or complete your personal data.

**Right to delete**. We will delete your personal data under the circumstances required by the PIPL. In case we fail to do so, you have the right to request the deletion in such circumstances as described by the law.

However, where the retention period prescribed by the applicable laws and regulations has not expired, or it is technically difficult to delete the personal data. However, we will cease the Processing of the personal data, except for storage and any necessary measure taken for security protection.

* **Right to request explanation**. You have the right to require us to explain our rules regarding the processing of personal data.
* **Right to withdraw.** You have the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal data carried out based on your consent. We will provide an easy way to withdraw consent. Your withdrawal of consent shall not affect the validity of any activity of processing of your personal data already carried out before the withdrawal based on your consent.
* **Right to opt-out of marketing communications**. You can opt-out of marketing-related emails by following the opt-out or unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of a marketing email, or by contacting us. You will continue to receive other non-marketing emails related to our Services. If you receive marketing text messages from us, you can opt out by replying STOP to our marketing message.

We will establish an accessible mechanism for you to exercise your rights. If we determine that your request to exercise your rights is not practical, we will let you know the reasons for such determination.

#### Consent

The Privacy Notice for China Residents is an integral part of the Privacy Policy.  Prior to using our Services, you have carefully read, fully understood and accepted the Privacy Policy, including the Privacy Notice for China Residents.  By accepting and consenting to the Privacy Policy, you have granted your consent to authorize VSCO to process your personal data in accordance with the Privacy Policy.

If you are a resident in China and younger than 14 years old, please do not use our Services or provide any of your personal data to VSCO. Please do not provide any personal data to VSCO if your parent or legal guardian has not accepted this Privacy Policy following discussion with you and granted separate consent to authorize VSCO to process your personal data in accordance with the Privacy Policy.

#### Contact us

You may contact us through our [Help Center](http://support.vsco.co/) with any questions regarding the processing of your personal data.
